（上条(かみじょう)）
学園都市最強のレベル５(ファイブ)が―
If Academy City's strongest Level 5...
学園都市最弱のレベル０(ゼロ)に
あっさり敗北したら
...loses pathetically to its weakest Level 0...
恐らく
このバカげた実験は中止になる
...then perhaps...
...this outrageous experiment will be suspended.
口で言うほど
簡単なことじゃないけど
Although it's not as easy as I'm making it sound,
it's something worth attempting.
やってみる価値はあるはずだ
そうだろう？　御坂(みさか)
～♪
Right, Misaka?
#14 Weakest vs Strongest
Strongest vs Weakest
Looks like it was wheat flour inside.
中身は小麦粉でしたってな
You've heard of "dust explosions" at least, right?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
なあ　お前
粉塵(ふんじん)爆発って言葉ぐれえ
聞いたことあるよな？
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
まったく…
Good grief.
さっき 身をもって
経験したばっかじゃねえか
Didn't I just learn my lesson?
I'd feel it too with this lack of oxygen.
酸素を奪われると
こっちも つらいんだっつうの
Damn, I thought I was gonna die.
ああ 死ぬかと思った
Rejoice, for you could be the first in the world, 'ya know?
喜べ　お前 ひょっとして
世界初じゃねえのか？
You pushed me to a near-death situation.
この俺を死ぬかもしれねえとこまで
追い詰めるだなんてさ
Try as hard as you want, but you won't get a step near me.
死にものぐるいで努力しても
一歩も近づけねえ
And even if you did get near me,
what could you possibly do to me?
かといって 仮に近づいたところで
お前に何ができるってんだ？
I can control any vector I come in touch with.
俺は 触れた物 全てのベクトルを
操ることができる
The second I come in touch with you,
俺が お前に触れたら最後
I'll blow up every single one of your veins and organs inside your body, okay?
全身の血管と内臓を
根こそぎ爆破ってことなんだけど
You got that processed in your brain yet?
そこんとこ
正しく理解してたのか？
But, okay,
まあ つっても
このアクセラレータを前に―
the fact you are standing and breathing before me,
Accelerator, is somewhat of a miracle.
今 こうして
呼吸してること そのものが―
奇跡なんだけどな
Asking for more is a bit of a luxury, don't you think?
それ以上を望むってのは
贅沢ってもんじゃねえの？
だから いいかげん 楽になれ！
So, lie down and rest already!!!
Damn you!!!
くそ！
Okay...
…たく
ハハハハッ… 面白(おもしれ)え　ちくしょう
This is interesting, damn.
Good, this is perfect.
いいぜ　最高に いいね
You got my blood jumping for joy now.
愉快にステキに決まっちまったぞ
You little...
お前は！
My right hand's power is working.
右手の力が効いてる
く… くそ！
Damn...
ハァ… ちくしょう
Damn this...
What the hell... is happening...
どういうことだ？　一体
（上条）
フッ… “負けたことがない”ね
So, you've never lost, huh?
You defeat all your enemies in one shot.
あらゆる敵を一撃で倒し
どんな攻撃も反射する
You deflect all attacks away.
People like you wouldn't know how to street fight.
そんなヤツが―
ケンカのやり方なんか
知ってるはずがねえよな
Don't get too cocky, thug!
ほえてんじゃねえぞ 三下(さんした)が！
What?!
なに？
Even they... do their best in fulfilling their lives...
あいつらだってな
精いっぱい生きてきたんだぞ
They do their best... living all they can...
全力を振り絞って 必死に生きて
...and these people who lived all they could...
精いっぱい努力してきた人間が―
なんだって―
...why do they have to end up being food for the likes of you?
てめえみたいな人間の食いものに
されなくっちゃなんねえんだよ？
Lived all they could, you say?
“精いっぱい生きてきた”？
Do their best in living all they can, you say?
“全力を振り絞って生きてきた”？
ハハハッ！　何だよ そりゃ
What is that bullshit?
Kill him.
殺せ！
What? What? What's this?
何だ 何だよ
何ですか？　そのザマは
In the end, you're just all talk and powerless.
結局 でかい口たたくだけで
大したことねえな
ほら　もう一発 かましてやるから
C'mon, I'll take care of you with one more hit,
so try your best coming out of the loser's bracket, eh?
カッコよく
敗者復活でもしてみろっての！
Compress... Compress...
圧縮 圧縮… 空気を圧縮
Compress air.
圧縮？　ハハッ…
いいぜ　愉快なこと思いついた
Compress... Good, I've come up with something fun!
What's the matter? Where did your bravado disappear to?
ほら！　さっきまでの威勢のよさは
どうしたんだ？
I need you to play along with me somewhat
or else this debt won't be settled.
お前には
まだまだ つきあってもらわなきゃ
割に合わねえんだっつうの
Accelerator!
（美琴(みこと)）アクセラレータ！
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）うん？
Freeze.
（美琴）動かないで
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）フン…
...Don't...
（上条）…めろ
（美琴）えっ？
...Don't... Misaka...
やめろ　御坂
Sorry.
（美琴）ごめん
（上条）ハッ…
You wished for nothing to be lost,
あんたは
何ひとつ失うことなく―
みんなで笑って
みんなで帰ることを願ってた
for everyone to be smiling,
for everyone to be able to make it back safely.
But that's not possible.
だけど それはムリ
So... sorry...
だから ごめん
I know this is selfish of me,
なんだかね
勝手なことかもしれないけどさ
but even so...
それでも…
...even so, I... I want you to live on...
それでも 私は きっと
あんたに生きてほしいんだと思う
DON'T!!!
やめろ！
Plasma?
（美琴）
プラズマ？
風の向きを操り １か所に集めて
プラズマを形成するなんて…
He controlled the direction of the winds,
gathered them into one spot,
and created plasma?!
（美琴）
こんなの
私の力じゃ どうしようもない
There's nothing my power can do against something like this...
風でも操れれば…
だけど そんな力なんて…
If I could control the winds, as well...
But, that kind of power's...
風？
Wind?
I'm quite sure that the plasma was formed by compressing nearby winds together.
多分 あのプラズマは 周りの風を
凝縮して作り出されたもの
Accelerator's calculating the flow of wind to control the plasma.
アクセラレータは―
風の流れを計算して
プラズマを制御してる
If so...
だとすれば…
お願い　起きて
あんたにやってほしいことがあるの
Please, wake up.
I need you to do something for me.
No, this is something only you can do.
ううん　あんたにしか
できないことがあるの
ムリを言ってるのは分かってる
だけど 一度でいいから起きて
I know this is asking for too much.
But, please, just wake up this one time!
たったひとつでいいから
私の願いを聞いて！
Just listen to my wish this one time!
I probably won't be able to save everyone...
私には きっと みんなを守れない
どれだけ もがいても 絶対に
...no matter how hard I try... I won't...
だから お願いだから…
...so... so please...
お願いだから あんたの力で
あいつの夢を守ってあげて！
...so please... I need your power to protect... his dream!!!
（御坂10032）
言葉の意味は分かりかねますが―
"I do not understand the meaning of your words,"
"but for some reason, they resonated very powerfully," comments MISAKA with utmost honesty.
なぜだか
その言葉は とても響きました
…と
ミサカは率直な感想を述べます
チッ… 風の計算を誤ったか
I miscalculated the winds?
なに？　何が起こってんだ？
What? What's happening?
俺の計算式に狂いはないはずだ
There shouldn't be any mistake in my calculations.
この不規則な動きは
どう考えても 自然の風じゃねえ
This irregular pattern of movement can't be natural wind no matter how you look at it.
あっ… まさか
It can't be...
Wait, I've heard of this.
待て　聞いたことがあんぞ
I remember that if you direct a certain special kind of electromagnetic wave at the motor of a power generator,
確か発電機のモーターってのは―
特殊な電磁波 浴びせっと
回転するって話が…
that'll make it start spinning...
この野郎！
You bitch...
ンンッ… 殺す！
I'll kill 'ya...
（美琴）させると思う？
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）ハッ…
You think I'd let you?
フッ…
図に乗ってんじゃねえぞ 格下が
Don't get too conceited, low class.
You're way too weak for me.
お前じゃ 俺に届きゃしねえよ
Perfect vision can only be measured as 2.0 - same idea.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
視力検査ってのは
2,0までしか測れねえだろう？
それと一緒さ
学園都市には 最高位のレベルが
５までしかねえから
The levels in this city only go up to 5,
which is why I'm reluctantly staying in this position.
しかたなく 俺は ここに
甘んじてるだけなんだっつうの
Don't... touch...
（上条）手を出すな
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）あっ…
そいつらに… 手を出すな
Don't... touch them...
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
フッ… 面白えよ お前
You're really something, 'ya know?
最高に面白えぞ！
You're really... the best!!!
ハアッ！
Grit your teeth well, "strongest" one.
歯を食いしばれよ 最強
俺の最弱は…
My "weakest" attack...
...might shake you up a little!!!
ちっとばっか響くぞ！
ウ～ン…
えっ… はい？
Huh?
（上条）みみみ… 御坂さん？
（御坂10032）うん？
Mi-Mi-Mi-Mi-Misaka-san?!
あれ？　なんで こんなハッピーな
イベントが起きてるんでせう？
Why am I experiencing such a happy event?
そんなフラグを立てた覚えは
皆無なんですけど
I don't remember raising any flags like this at all.
"To inform you properly, let it be known you were the one who came grabbing me,"  recites MISAKA.
念のために伝えておくと―
手を握ってきたのは
あなたのほうです
…と ミサカは語ります
N-No, it's not true!
ウ… ウソだ
クッ…
麻酔が首から下に効いてる状況で
You're saying I'm so sexually deprived that even under anesthesia,
それでも 勝手に
手が女の子の胸に―
my hand went for a girl's breasts on its own?
向かってしまうほどの
欲求不満だなんて…
That's so not true!!!
そんなのウソだ！
うん？　あなたが行ったのは
ミサカの手を握ったところまでです
"All you did was grab MISAKA's hands," adds MISAKA.
…と ミサカは補足説明します
"Moving your hands to this location was MISAKA's will,"
この位置まで手を持ってきたのは
ミサカの意思ですので
"so you are not at any fault," answers MISAKA.
あなたに非があることでは
ありませんが
…と ミサカは答えます
ミサカは単に 生体電気の流れから
"MISAKA was simply using the electric flow in your body..."
あなたの脳波と心拍数を
計測していただけです
"...to calculate your heartbeat and brainwaves," replies MISAKA.
…と ミサカは返答します
Wait, so my hand is touching them right now?
あれ？ …てことは
この手は今 触れてるの？
麻酔のせいで
何にも感じないんですけど
I can't feel anything because of the anesthesia though.
指１本 動かせないし
Nor can I move a finger.
な… なんたる不幸！
Such... Such misfortune!!!
（御坂10032）
あなたの言語中枢に
異常はありませんか？
"I did not detect any irregularities in your brain's speech center though," suggests MISAKA with a bit of anxiety.
…と
ミサカは不安要素を述べてみます
ハァ… まあ
Well, looks like we both made it back somehow.
お互い
なんとか帰ってこれましたな
"Regarding that," replies MISAKA,
それについてなのですが
…と ミサカは答えます
"MISAKA isn't able to return to the same world you are in yet," answers MISAKA honestly.
ミサカは まだ あなたと同じ世界に
帰ることはできません
…と ミサカは正直に告げます
えっ？　まさか まだ実験が…
Wait... they're still performing the experiments?
"No, that is not it."
いえ　そうではなくて
実験は
アクセラレータの敗北とともに―
"The experiment, following Accelerator's defeat,
is going to be suspended," explains MISAKA cordially.
中止に向かうことが
決定したようです
…と
ミサカは懇切丁寧に報告します
（御坂10032）ハァ…
（上条）うん？
ミサカが問題にしているのは
ミサカの体のことです
"MISAKA's problem is an issue with MISAKA's body," explains MISAKA.
…と ミサカは説明します
（上条）体？
（御坂10032）はい
Body?
"Yes."
"MISAKA's body is a clone body created from Oneesama's cells to begin with,"
もともと ミサカの体は―
お姉様の体細胞から
作られたクローンであり
そこへ 更に
さまざまな薬品を投与することで
"and with the addition of many kinds of chemicals, this led to accelerated growth," explains MISAKA.
急速に成長を促した個体です
…と ミサカは説明します
"Thus, the duration of an already shortened lifespan
of a clone is shortened even more."
よって ただでさえ寿命の短い
体細胞クローンが―
更に短命になっているのです
"Do you understand?" asks MISAKA.
…と 言って分かりますか？
…と ミサカは聞いてみます
"That is why MISAKA will be staying at a research facility to adjust MISAKA's body..."
だから
一時的に研究施設のお世話になって
個体を調整する必要があるのですが
聞いてますか？
"Are you listening?" as MISAKA stares at you.
…と
ミサカは あなたをにらみつけます
（上条）調整？
（御坂10032）はい
Adjust?
"Yes."
急速な成長を促す
ホルモンバランスを整え
"By adjusting the hormones that expedite the body's growth..."
細胞核の分裂速度を調整することで
"...and the speed of cell segmentation, a certain amount of lifespan may be recoverable," answers MISAKA.
ある程度の寿命を
回復させることができます
…と ミサカは答えます
それでは
"Well then."
Hey, wait!
お… おい 待てよ
調整って 治るのか？
Adjusting... will that cure you?
（御坂10032）
大丈夫　すぐに会えます
"Don't worry."
"MISAKA will see you soon," declares MISAKA.
…と ミサカは ここに宣言します
まあ 大きい問題はなさそうだね
Well, looks like there's nothing serious.
しかし 君は よっぽど この病室が
気に入っちゃったみたいだね
But you sure have an affection for this room.
まあ 当分は安静にしておくことだ
Rest well for the time being.
（ｶｴﾙ医師）じゃ またあとで
（上条）はい　先生
See you later then.
Thanks, Doc.
ああ　起きた？
Ah, you up?
御坂か
It's you, Misaka?
Afterwards, what did-
お前 あれから…
（美琴）
はい　お見舞い
Here, a gift for the sick.
Ahh...
デパ地下で
なんか高そうなの選んできたから
I just picked some expensive looking ones from the basement of the department store.
まあ そこそこ
おいしいクッキーだと思うんだけど
I'm sure these cookies are delicious to a certain extent.
う～ん… クッキーというなら
お手製がベストでは？
Home-made cookies are the best, you know?
あんたね 私に
どんなキャラ期待してんのよ？
What kind of character are you hoping I'd be?
You know?
あえて 不器用なキャラが
不器用なりに頑張ってみた―
The clumsy character that tries clumsily hard and makes some crumbled cookies.
ボロボロクッキーっていうのがね
分かんねえかなぁ
You don't get it, huh?
I said, what kind of character are you hoping I'd be?
だから
なに期待してんのよ？ あんたは
ウワッ！
ストップ！　マジでストップ！
Stop!
Really, stop!
Gosh!
（美琴）まったく
（上条）あっ そうだ
Ah, that's right.
朝方に
御坂妹が やって来たんだけどさ
Your sister came by early this morning.
（美琴）
そっか
I see...
それじゃ 帰るね
I'll be going now.
けどさ…
Hey...
If you hadn't given them your DNA map,
お前が
ＤＮＡマップを提供しなけりゃ―
そもそも妹達(シスターズ)は生まれてくることも
できなかったんだ
then the sisters would've never been born.
あの実験は
いろいろ間違ってたけどさ
Even though that experiment was wrong in many ways,
あいつらが
生まれてきたことだけは―
the fact that they were born... was, I think, something you should be proud of...
きっと
お前は誇るべきなんだと思う
私のせいで １万人以上の妹達(シスターズ)が
殺されちゃったのに？
But more than 10,000 Sisters have died because of me...
（上条）それでもだよ
（美琴）あっ…
Even so...
（上条）
あいつらは
きっと お前のことを恨んでない
I'm sure they don't hate you.
生まれてこなければ―
Had they never been born, they wouldn't have been able to experience happiness or sadness.
喜ぶことも 悲しむことも
できなかったはずだから
So, it's okay for you to smile.
だから お前は笑ってていいんだよ
お前が守りたかったあいつらは―
Those sisters that you wanted to protect so much...
自分の傷の痛みを他人に押しつけて
満足するような―
...aren't people that satisfy themselves by forcing their own wounds and pains on to others, right?
そんな ちっぽけな連中じゃ
ねえんだろう？
See ya.
ウ～ン… うん？
ウワッ！
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻(とうま)　何か言うことは？
Touma, got something to say?
えっと…
Umm...
おはよう？
Good morning?
待て待て！　今回は シャレや
冗談では済まない傷なんだって
Wait, wait!
They said my injuries this time are pretty serious and stuff.
Heck, shouldn't you show some worry for the master of the house?
つうか てめえは
家主さんに対する心配とか少しは…
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）心配したもん！
（上条）あっ…
I was worried!
心配したもん
I was worried for you.
（上条）
ごめん
Sorry.
当麻は 今回も 今回も 今回も
Touma, you put all the burden on yourself this time,
and this time, and this time, right?
１人で問題を抱えていたんだね
If you don't consult us a bit,
then I might really need to lecture you.
少しは相談とかしてくれないと―
いいかげんに
本気で説教しなくちゃならないかも
フゥ… まあ あんまり言及しても
しかたがないから いいんだけどね
Oh well, digging too much into this wouldn't do any good.
それで 結局
当麻は何のために戦ったの？
So, what did you fight for, in the end, Touma?
（上条）
自分のためだろう
For myself, I bet.
～♪
Next Episode
（上条）
夏の海で 両親との感動の再会
…だったはずが
A touching reunion with my parents by the summer sea,
or at least, that was the original plan...
とんでもない魔術の出現で
大パニックに！
But with the appearance of a dangerous magic spell, now we're in a panic?
This person is... my mother?
こ… この人が 俺の母さん？
次回 「御使堕し(エンゼルフォール)」
Next time, "Angel Fall".
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる
When science and magic cross paths,
this epic will begin!